<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<BaseGameText>
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_VLR_ODA_NAME">
			<Text>Oda Nobunaga</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--UA-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_VLR_ODA_UA_NAME">
			<Text>Tenka Fubu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_VLR_ODA_UA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Capturing a city provides a burst of loyalty (33%) to all cities within 10 tiles. All Walls produce +2 Culture. Gain the Tanegashima Gunner unique unit with Gunpowder and, upon researching Gunpowder, receive a free Tanegashima Gunner in every original capital you control.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--DOM-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_VLR_ODA">
			<Text>
				Japan calls, Oda Nobunaga. Through cunning, treachery and intrigue, you unified many of the warring states under your own banner. None standing against you could face your might. Now the time has come once again to take up your sword. Use your talents and skills to their utmost, and lead Japan into a bright and everlasting tomorrow.
			</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Civilopedia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_TITLE">
			<Text>Oda Nobunaga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Oda Nobunaga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_QUOTE">
			<Text>"Look at the world, within the sea, there is no immortal."</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Oda Nobunaga (23 June 1534 – 21 June 1582) was a Japanese daimyō and one of the leading figures of the Sengoku period. He is regarded as the first "Great Unifier" of Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>Nobunaga was head of the powerful Oda clan of Owari Province and launched a war against other samurai to unify Japan in the 1560s. Nobunaga emerged as the most powerful daimyō in Japan, overthrowing the nominally ruling shōgun Ashikaga Yoshiaki and dissolved the Ashikaga Shogunate in 1573, conquering most of Honshu and defeating the Ikkō-ikki rebels by the 1580s. Nobunaga's rule was noted for innovative military tactics, fostering free trade, reform of Japan's civil government, and encouraging the start of the Momoyama historical art period, but also the brutal suppression of opponents, eliminating those who refused to cooperate or yield to his demands. Nobunaga was killed in the Honno-ji Incident in 1582 when his retainer Akechi Mitsuhide ambushed him in Kyoto which compelled him to commit sepuku. Nobunaga was succeeded by Toyotomi Hideyoshi who along with Tokugawa Iyeyasu completed his war of unification shortly afterwards.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Nobunaga was an influential figure in Japanese history and is regarded as one of three great unifiers along with his retainers Toyotomi Hideyoshi and Tokugawa Ieyasu. Nobunaga initiated the Azuchi-Momoyama period of Japan partially named after his castle, Azuchi Castle, which led to the end of the Sengoku period and eventual transition to the Edo period.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--Diplomacy-->
		<!--FIRST MEET-->
		<!--First AI line-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>We hope for a fair and just relationship with you, who are renowned for military bravery.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to visit nearby City-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>One of my generals lives nearby. I invite you to come and discuss matters further over a traditional tea.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI accepts Human invitation-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>I am honoured to go.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to exchange Capital Information-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>It is prudent that we exchange the locations of our Capitals, that we better understand each other.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--GREETINGS-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Proceed.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--DELEGATION-->
		<!--AI Accepts-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Your delegation will be treated with respect, provided they do not make fools of themselves.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>We will not accept your delegates' entry at this time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>I have dispatched some men - a delegation. They bring gifts, including a ceremonial sword.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--OPEN BORDERS-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>For now, I have no objections.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI rejects from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>That cannot be permitted.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>I would be grateful if you agreed on the following proposal.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--DECLARE FRIENDSHIP-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Very well. I accept our friendship, but do not betray this trust.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects from human -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Sorry, but no.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests friendship from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>You have proven yourself a worthy and mighty friend to my own. Do you accept this offer of friendship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human accepts AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Well done.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human rejects AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>That is unfortunate.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--ALLIANCE-->
		<!--AI Requests an alliance from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>States that conflict with one another are weak. But together, we can find greater purpose. Do you agree?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI warns player for border troops-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>I see your troops assembling at my border. If it is war you seek, then declare it now. If not, I advise you retreat.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--TRADE-->
		<!--AI Accepts Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Very well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Maybe another time.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--DENOUNCE-->
		<!--From Human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Your tongue is sharp, but it is worthless without a matching sword.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--From AI-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>You are a disgrace to your people! You are no friend of my shogunate. (Denounces You.)</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--DECLARE WAR-->
		<!--Human Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Pitiful fool! Now we shall destroy you!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>I hereby inform you of our intention to wipe out your civilization from this world.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--MAKE PEACE-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>It was an honour to fight you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI refuses human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>I will not accept your cowardice.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>If we do not end here, it will become a war of attrition. The time has come to cease fighting.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--DEFEAT-->
		<!--AI is Defeated-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>You were much wiser than I thought.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is Defeated (will see this in hotseat)-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>I had hoped you be wiser, more cunning. You disappoint me.</Text>
		</Row>


		<!--LEADER AGENDA-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_VLR_ODA_NAME">
			<Text>Great Unifier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_VLR_ODA_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Dislikes neighboring Civilizations, especially if they are weak; likes Civilizations that are further away, especially if they are strong.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_VLR_ODA_REASON_NEAR_STRONG">
			<Text>(You are a neighboring nation, but strong enough to defend yourself.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_AGENDA_VLR_ODA_UNIFIER_NEAR_STRONG">
			<Text>Oda dislikes that you stand in the way of Unification.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_VLR_ODA_REASON_NEAR_WEAK">
			<Text>(You are a weak neighbor, ripe for the picking.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_AGENDA_VLR_ODA_UNIFIER_NEAR_WEAK">
			<Text>Oda believes you should be crushed soon in the name of Unification.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_LEADER_VLR_ODA_REASON_FAR_STRONG">
			<Text>(You are a strong nation and do not neighbor Japan.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_AGENDA_VLR_ODA_UNIFIER_FAR_STRONG">
			<Text>Oda thinks your strong nation could make a useful ally for Unification.</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_LEADER_VLR_ODA_REASON_FAR_WEAK">
			<Text>(You do not neighbor Japan, but have a weak army.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_AGENDA_VLR_ODA_UNIFIER_FAR_WEAK">
			<Text>Oda believes that, while weak, you could play a role in his Unification campaigns.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--AI Kudos-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>Yours is a nation worthy of respect and one we can all learn from. Well done.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Warnings-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_VLR_ODA_ANY">
			<Text>If you wish to be a respected leader, I suggest your people begin taking up arms. A weak warlord is soon to be a dead warlord.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--UU-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_VLR_ODA_UU_NAME">
			<Text>Tanegashima Gunner</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_VLR_ODA_UU_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unique Renaissance era unit that replaces the Musketman. Gains a [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength bonus against units from earlier eras.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_VLR_ODA_UU_NAME">
			<Text>Tanegashima Gunner</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_VLR_ODA_UU_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Unique Renaissance era unit that replaces the Musketman. Gains a [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength bonus against units from earlier eras.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_VLR_ODA_UU_NAME">
			<Text>Tanegashima Gunner</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_VLR_ODA_UU_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength against units from earlier eras.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_VLR_ODA_UU_MOD_PREVIEW_TEXT">
			<Text>+7 against units from earlier eras.</Text>
		</Row>
	</BaseGameText>
</GameData>